<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ben Silver</title>
    <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ben Silver</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://benjamin-silver.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Motivated impressions and perceptions of other people</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/beliefs_others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/beliefs_others/</guid>
      <description>How would you react if you found out that your partner has been unfaithful? Or that the slacker in your high school class is now immensely successful? We make predictions about how people will act all the time - what happens when those predictions are wrong? In order to form cohesive representations of others, we often need to integrate conflicting information about them. Furthermore, our pre-existing feelings towards these people, as well as our motivations and goals, influence how and when we update our beliefs about them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of Teaching Roles and Responsibilities</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/responsibilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/responsibilities/</guid>
      <description>Instructor of record Psychology and the Internet Term: Fall 2024 Lead Instructor: Me! Course Details: The course focuses on the intersection between Psychology research and the Internet. The first half of the course explores how the Internet can serve as a new tool/methodology/data source to ask classic psychology questions. The midterm assignment asks students to create a programming tutorial that explains how to access and work with one type of Internet data (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivated self-perception over time</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/beliefs_self/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/beliefs_self/</guid>
      <description>[Under construction]
It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to update one&amp;rsquo;s beliefs about oneself: What did we used to be like, and when/how/why did we change? In this study, I investigated how self-views, and memory for previous self-views, changed in response to the 2020 U.S. presidential election.
Silver, B.M., Meyer, M.L., Davachi, L., Ochsner, K.N. (under review). “Did I really used to be like that?” Self-views and memory across the 2020 U.S. presidential election.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching feedback</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/feedback/</guid>
      <description>Included on this page is student feedback from courses in which I taught my own lab section. I have taught one section of a Research Methods class with Professor Niall Bolger on Zoom (during COVID-19), and three sections (over two semesters) of a Research Methods class with Professor Kevin Ochsner, in person.
I divide my feedback into two sections, based on feedback topic. For each section, I provide a brief note about why this topic of feedback is important to me, followed by several quotes from student evaluations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching/Diversity Statements</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/statement/</guid>
      <description>You can find a PDF of my teaching statement here. You can find a PDF of my diversity statement here. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivated beliefs online</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/beliefs_online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/beliefs_online/</guid>
      <description>[Under construction]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the impacts of motion and physiological noise during fMRI</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/motion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/motion/</guid>
      <description>Functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) has changed psychology and neuroscience - the technology has made it possible to visualize the neural effects of both external stimuli, such as images or videos, and internal stimuli, such as thoughts or mental images. However, as all fMRI researchers know, fMRI signal is far from perfect, and is influenced by things like how much the participant moves and even how and when they breathe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restricted interests in Autism Spectrum Disorder</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/asd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/asd/</guid>
      <description>We all have things that we&amp;rsquo;re interested in: Hobbies, favorite tv shows, topic areas we can&amp;rsquo;t learn enough about. Most of the time, we are able to inhibit our desires related to our interests - talking about them, thinking about them - when it is socially appropriate. Some children and adults with Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) are less able to modulate their thought patterns to match what is appropriate for the situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample teaching materials</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/examples/</guid>
      <description>On this page you&amp;rsquo;ll find two sample teaching materials that are representative of what I use in the classroom. For each material, I&amp;rsquo;ve included some annotations to provide insight into my thought process when creating them.
To see an example of a coding tutorial, click here. To see an example of my slides, click here. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Original Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>In Fall 2024, I&amp;rsquo;m teaching an original undergraduate seminar, via the Columbia Teaching Scholars program.
You can view an interactive version of the syllabus here. Certain elements of the syllabus (such as some course topics and policies) were intentionally kept open to incorporate student input and so were changed once the semester began. You can view the original version of the syllabus, without student input, here . Alternatively, you can view a rough draft I made as part of the Columbia CTL Innovative Course Design Seminar (ICDS), with annotations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/templates/post/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/templates/post/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com .
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Braintrainer</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/templates/projects/math-brain-trainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/templates/projects/math-brain-trainer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surprise Surprise</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/templates/articles/article/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/templates/articles/article/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for your support! Hello. If you like this template, I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to get a coffee donation :)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
