<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ben Silver</title>
    <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ben Silver</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://benjamin-silver.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Impression formation and updating</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/others/</guid>
      <description>How would you react if you found out that your partner has been unfaithful? Or that the slacker in your high school class is now immensely successful? We make predictions about how people will act all the time - what happens when those predictions are wrong? In order to form cohesive representations of others, we often need to integrate conflicting information about them. Furthermore, our pre-existing feelings towards these people, as well as our motivations and goals, influence how and when we update our beliefs about them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of Teaching Roles and Responsibilities</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/responsibilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/responsibilities/</guid>
      <description>Instructor of record Research Methods: Data Science, Justice, and Social Change Term: Fall 2025 Lead Instructor: Me! Course Details: This course provides the rigorous data science training and core content knowledge students need to use data science to effect policy changes that promote a more just society. To explore these topics, students engage in in-class discussions on the intersections between psychology and justice. Students also conduct their own research project by analyzing a found dataset, with a focus on justice-oriented outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human behavior in the digital sphere</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/internet/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever changed your beliefs because of something you read online?
The online world is filled with information - most true, some not - and our motivations impact whether and how we incorporate that information into our world view. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in how we can apply models of motivated belief change about other people to information encountered in the online world. In addition, I&amp;rsquo;m interested in what tools or aspects of the online world can we target to most effectively stop the spread of misinformation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching feedback</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/feedback/</guid>
      <description>Included on this page is student feedback from four courses:
Psychology and the Internet, developed course and was instructor of record (Fall 2024) Research Methods, lab section instructor/TA to Professor Kevin Ochsner (two sections in Fall 2022 and one section in Spring 2022) Research Methods, lab section instructor/TA to Professor Niall Bolger (Spring 2021, on Zoom during COVID-19) I divide my feedback into two sections, based on feedback topic. For each section, I provide a brief note about why this topic of feedback is important to me, followed by several quotes from student evaluations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching/Diversity Statements</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/statement/</guid>
      <description>You can find a PDF of my teaching statement here. You can find a PDF of my diversity statement here. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing self-perceptions</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/self/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/self/</guid>
      <description>Is the person you are now the person you were five years ago?
It&amp;rsquo;s possible to update one&amp;rsquo;s beliefs about oneself: What did we used to be like, and when/how/why did we change? The self-concept can change in response to any number of events: significant personal events such as entering college, or large societal events like a presidential election. Different types of events will cause changes to different facets of the self-concept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Older projects</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/older/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/research/older/</guid>
      <description>Reducing impacts of motion and physiological noise during fMRI Functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) has changed psychology and neuroscience - the technology has made it possible to visualize the neural effects of both external stimuli, such as images or videos, and internal stimuli, such as thoughts or mental images. However, as all fMRI researchers know, fMRI signal is far from perfect, and is influenced by things like how much the participant moves and even how and when they breathe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample teaching materials</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/examples/</guid>
      <description>On this page you&amp;rsquo;ll find two sample teaching materials that are representative of what I use in the classroom. For each material, I&amp;rsquo;ve included some annotations to provide insight into my thought process when creating them.
To see an example of a coding tutorial, click here. To see an example of my slides, click here. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Original Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>In Fall 2024, I taught an original undergraduate seminar called Psychology and the Internet, via the Columbia Teaching Scholars program.
You can view an interactive version of the syllabus here. Certain elements of the syllabus (such as some course topics and policies) were intentionally kept open to incorporate student input and so were changed once the semester began. You can view the original version of the syllabus, without student input, here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/templates/post/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/templates/post/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com .
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Braintrainer</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/templates/projects/math-brain-trainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/templates/projects/math-brain-trainer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surprise Surprise</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/templates/articles/article/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/templates/articles/article/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for your support! Hello. If you like this template, I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to get a coffee donation :)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
