<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ben Silver</title>
    <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ben Silver</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Summary of Teaching Roles and Responsibilities</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/responsibilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/responsibilities/</guid>
      <description>Curriculum developer and co-instructor BRAINYAC Terms: January 2020-August 2022 Lead Instructor: Diana Li Course Details: BRAINYAC is a program aimed at high school students from underrepresented backgrounds to provide an opportunity to learn neuroscience and conduct science research. Each year, a cohort of 15-20 students is admitted. In the spring, students come to Columbia on Saturday mornings to learn neuroscience and research skills. Activities include a sheep brain dissection, wet-lab skills such as pipetting and dilutions, and Python tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching feedback</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/feedback/</guid>
      <description>Included on this page is student feedback from courses in which I taught my own lab section. I have taught one section of a Research Methods class with Professor Niall Bolger on Zoom (during COVID-19), and three sections (over two semesters) of a Research Methods class with Professor Kevin Ochsner, in person.
I divide my feedback into two sections, based on feedback topic. For each section, I provide a brief note about why this topic of feedback is important to me, followed by several quotes from student evaluations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Statements</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/statement/</guid>
      <description>[Under Construction]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample teaching materials</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/examples/</guid>
      <description>[Under Construction]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Original Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>As part of the Columbia CTL Innovative Course Design Seminar, I created a course from scratch.
The course focuses on the intersection between Psychology research and the Internet. The first half of the course explores how the Internet can serve as a new tool/methodology/data source to ask classic psychology questions. The midterm assignment asks students to create a programming tutorial that explains how to access and work with one type of Internet data (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
