<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ben Silver</title>
    <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ben Silver</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Summary of Teaching Roles and Responsibilities</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/responsibilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/responsibilities/</guid>
      <description>Instructor of record Psychology and the Internet Term: Fall 2024 Lead Instructor: Me! Course Details: The course focuses on the intersection between Psychology research and the Internet. The first half of the course explores how the Internet can serve as a new tool/methodology/data source to ask classic psychology questions. The midterm assignment asks students to create a programming tutorial that explains how to access and work with one type of Internet data (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching feedback</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/feedback/</guid>
      <description>Included on this page is student feedback from courses in which I taught my own lab section. I have taught one section of a Research Methods class with Professor Niall Bolger on Zoom (during COVID-19), and three sections (over two semesters) of a Research Methods class with Professor Kevin Ochsner, in person.
I divide my feedback into two sections, based on feedback topic. For each section, I provide a brief note about why this topic of feedback is important to me, followed by several quotes from student evaluations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching/Diversity Statements</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/statement/</guid>
      <description>You can find a PDF of my teaching statement here. You can find a PDF of my diversity statement here. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample teaching materials</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/examples/</guid>
      <description>On this page you&amp;rsquo;ll find two sample teaching materials that are representative of what I use in the classroom. For each material, I&amp;rsquo;ve included some annotations to provide insight into my thought process when creating them.
To see an example of a coding tutorial, click here. To see an example of my slides, click here. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Original Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjamin-silver.com/teaching/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>In Fall 2024, I&amp;rsquo;m teaching an original undergraduate seminar, via the Columbia Teaching Scholars program.
You can view an interactive version of the syllabus here. Certain elements of the syllabus (such as some course topics and policies) were intentionally kept open to incorporate student input and so were changed once the semester began. You can view the original version of the syllabus, without student input, here. Alternatively, you can view a rough draft I made as part of the Columbia CTL Innovative Course Design Seminar (ICDS), with annotations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
